<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dieter Ladenhauf</title>
    <link>https://didiladi.github.io/cv/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dieter Ladenhauf</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://didiladi.github.io/cv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://didiladi.github.io/cv/00-petersgasse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://didiladi.github.io/cv/00-petersgasse/</guid>
      <description>8
Years
   09/1997
-
07/2005
 Bundesrealgymnasium (BRG) Petersgasse, Graz
    Bezeichnung Beschreibung     Focus: Natural sciences   Graduation: Matriculation (equals A Levels) on June 22nd , 2005     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://didiladi.github.io/cv/01-bachelor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://didiladi.github.io/cv/01-bachelor/</guid>
      <description>3.5
Years
   10/2005
-
02/2010
 Bachelor&#39;s Programme of Software Development and Business Management, Graz University of Technology
    Bezeichnung Beschreibung     Motivation: The writing of software is a very challenging task, because there is a high amount of creativity and thinking outside-of-the-box involved. This is the reason, why there was just one choice after finishing my school: I had to study software engineering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://didiladi.github.io/cv/02-kapsch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://didiladi.github.io/cv/02-kapsch/</guid>
      <description>   08/2008
 Summer internship, Kapsch CarrierCom AG - work was performed at the Institute for Software Technology at Graz University of Technology
    Bezeichnung Beschreibung     Field of responsibility: Software development of a social media streaming portal using Java Server Faces. Within this time, I collected my first experience with agile methods.     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://didiladi.github.io/cv/03-master/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://didiladi.github.io/cv/03-master/</guid>
      <description>2
Years
   02/2010
-
03/2012
 Master&#39;s Programme of Software Development and Business Management, Graz University of Technology
    Bezeichnung Beschreibung     Main focus: &amp;ldquo;Web and Data Science&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Knowledge Management&amp;rdquo;   Master&amp;rsquo;s thesis: &amp;ldquo;Liquid Diagrams - A Suite of Information Visualisation Gadgets&amp;rdquo;, Institute of Interactive Systems and Data Science
Liquid Diagrams, a suite of Flex-based visualizations and its underlying framework was extended in the context of this thesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://didiladi.github.io/cv/04-eegs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://didiladi.github.io/cv/04-eegs/</guid>
      <description>3
M
   03/2010
-
06/2010
 Institute of Computer Graphics and Knowledge Visualisation, Graz University of Technology
    Bezeichnung Beschreibung     Type of employment: Study assistant with marginal employment   Field of responsibility: Mentoring of students in the course &amp;ldquo;Design and Development of Large Systems&amp;rdquo; and correcting of student exercises.     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://didiladi.github.io/cv/05-dynatrace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://didiladi.github.io/cv/05-dynatrace/</guid>
      <description>5
Years
   07/2012
-
ongoing
 Backend Software engineer in the area Application Performance Management (APM), Dynatrace Austria GmbH, Linz
    Bezeichnung Beschreibung     Field of responsibility 2012 - 2013: At the beginning of my time at Dynatrace, I was responsible for the development of a SWT-based rich client. Later, my focus shifted towards the development of the web-UI using GWT in the area of real user monitoring (RUM).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://didiladi.github.io/cv/06-bildungskarenz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://didiladi.github.io/cv/06-bildungskarenz/</guid>
      <description>1
Y
   07/2017
-
06/2018
 Educational leave: Master’s Programme of Computer Science, Graz University of Technology
    Bezeichnung Beschreibung Punkte10     Description: Lifelong learning is an important aspect in the field of software engineering. That&amp;rsquo;s the reason why I decided to take a yearlong educatioal leave. During this timespan, I acquired a profound knowledge in the field of machine learning, one of my main interests.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>